#### BRIFF

Senior Web Application Developer, with a demonstrated history of working in the internet industry. Skilled in developing modern, user friendly web applications. 5+ year of experience. Freelancer since 2018.

Birthdate: 1983/10/14, Fulda, Germany Languages: German (native), English (fluent)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2018 - 2019 jambit GmbH, Munich · Senior Software Architect (extern)

> Customer: Southern german car manufacturer · Project: AOD / AMD 2018-2019 extension development and migrations for an existing angular frameworks - setup and extension of various frontend libraries - feature development for an existing Angular application - coordination after hand-over of a living styleguide from 3rd party - extension and feature development for multiple Java BFF applications (Spring, Spring WebFlux) - unit, integration and E2E testing in JavaScript and Java - refactoring of an existing E2E test framework based on Protractor - extension and refactoring of CICD libraries and pipelines - extension and development of build and release processes with Jenkins - deployments and maintenance within an AWS infrastructure with Cloudfoundry

support for team-restructuring - coordination and support for external feature teams - support, coordination and onboarding of new team members - active participation in team environment

task + sprint planning - coordination with business and technical stakeholders coordination of architectural decision with architecture board - consultant for UX + design topics

#### 2013 - 2018 SinnerSchrader, Munich · (Senior) Product Engineer

development of application architectures - implementation + maintenance of web + single-page applications - feature implementation in JavaScript, HTML + CSS frameworks supported for production: Angular, AngularJS, React - setup of frontend build + release processes in Grunt, Gulp + Webpack - production releases + deployments - custom tool + script development in nodejs

frontend lead for small project teams - onboarding + support for new colleagues support + development of junior and midlevel developers

task + sprint planing - coordination with business, technical + creative stakeholders - working onsite with customer, other feature teams in Munich, Hamburg and Düsseldorf

#### Projects (excerpt)

# Customer: Audi Business Innovation GmbH · Project: UI Components · 2018

setup, extension and development of a Living Styleguides for angular, based on an existing React based Styleguide - setup and coordination of theming + whitelabel architecture - feature development of components with Angular + (S)CSS - task und sprint planing - coordination with business, technical and creative

# Customer: Allianz · Project: MyInvest · 2017 - 2018

frontend lead for Angular application - feature development in Angular - setup + implementation of data layer using ngrx - integration with RESTful webservices implementation of custom charting library with d3.js - release and deployment setup with AWS + Jenkins - setup + customization of E2E tests using Protractor -E2E test planing + implementation

#### Customer: Allianz · Project: HVB Komponenten · 2017

implementation of custom, fully-responsive interface components with Angular technical design + implementation of custom chart components - coordination with business, technical + creative stakeholders

# CONTACT



- Munich
- github.com/chunksnbits
- in linkedin.com/in/daniel-eißing

- ■ Typescript
- Javascript
- HTMLICSS
- ■ Angular
- ReactiveX | NgRx | Redux
- ■ Testing | Karma | Jest | Protractor
- React
- □ □ □ Progressive Web Apps
- SCSS
- □ □ d3.js
- Git
- Webpack | NPM Scripts
- CICD | Jenkins | Github Hooks | Gitlabs
- Living Styleguides | Patternplate | Storybook
- ■ NodeJS
- Java | Spring | WebFlux
- □ □ □ Cloud Infastructure | CloudFoundry
- ■ AWS Serverless
- □ □ □ Databases | GraphQL | DynamoDB | SQL
- Scrum
- ■ UX+Design Tools | Sketch | Adobe Suite
- Developer Communities | Support
- Coaching | Junior Development

# **TECHNOLOGIES + SKILLS**

#### Customer: BMW · Project: eRetail · 2014 - 2017

frontend lead for development of multiple fully responsive AngularJS applications and MVPs - design + implementation of application architecture - feature development in AngularJS - implementation of product features + bugfixing for React application - implementation of fully responsive + provider independent chat application w/ drag + drop functionality - integration of chat multiple chat providers and integration in customer websites in different markets - setup and maintenace for build, release + deployment processes

frontend lead for small development teams - onboarding and mentoring of new team members - coaching for junior und intermediate developers

task und sprint planing - coordination with business, technical and creatives stakeholders - coordination of technical requirements - knowledge and architecture transfer to 3rd party providers

## Customer: BMW · Partner: QAWare · Project: Connected Drive · 2015 - 2016

Feature development in fully responsive Typescript-based AngularJS application - setup + support of frontend architecture - tool development in JavaScript - coordination with customer and external design agency - work on premise (Munich)

## Customer: Allianz · Project: Patttern library · 2014 - 2015

Planing and implementation of architecture for component based styleguide in VanillaJS + jQuery - component + feature implementation in JavaScript - build setup in Grunt - build migration to Webpack - coordination with technical + creative stakeholders - support + bugfixing

#### Customer: eplus smartkauf · Project: Proof of Concept «tarifs» · 2014

Implementation of proof of concept for tarif integration into existing Hybris shop - integration into Java backend application - coordination with Hybris feature team - project locations: Düsseldorf + Hamburg

# 2013 **TomTec Imaging Systems GmbH, Munich** · Software Developer

Feature implementation for reporting application in Java and JavaScript - unit, integration and E2E testing in Java - redesign and extension of Selenium based E2E testing framework in Ruby - feature implementation for C++ data conversion utility - unit and integration testing in C++

## **EDUCATION**

## 2013 University of Koblenz/Landau Studies of Computervisualistik

Studies in computer science, with focus areas: computergraphics, interface design and arts - student assistant for the Institute for Web Science - division: Semantic Web

#### Degree

Diplom Informatik

#### Awards

Young Talent Award 2011 Knowledge Management Working Group Karlsruhe.

# Publications (excerpt)

Scherp, Eißing, Staab - Analysis and comparison of modelbreas for individual and organisational knowledge work - Aufsatz - Tagungsband der MKWI 2012 ■

Scherp, Eißing, Staab - strukt - A Pattern System for Integrating Individual and Organizational Knowledge Work. - Konferenzbeitrag - The Semantic Web - ISWC 2011 🗷

# PERSONAL PROJECTS (EXCERPT)

2019 -tim-er-

MVP with goal of evaluating current technical topics, e.g.: React hooks, Redux Saga, CICD Integration in github - focused on early runnable version - status: alpha

Demo 🖸

Repository 🖸

2018 Technologie Radar

Proof of Concept with goal of evaluating technical topics, e.g.: d3js integration in React, React Contexts, Rendering Web Components with React - status: proof of concept (no further development planned)

Demo 🖸

Repository 🔀